so the first concept we will learn in
fault tolerance is dependability
dependability is a quality of delivered
service meaning a characteristic of
delivered service that justifies relying
on the system to provide its service
so pretty much a dependable system is
one that provides the service in a way
that makes us expect it to provide it
correctly and in a dependable way now
the service actually has two definitions
one is the specified service which is
what the behavior of the system should
look like and then we have delivered
service which is actual behavior this is
the behavior we actually got out of the
system so we could say that
dependability is really about can we
expect the delivered service to match
the specified service can we get what we
are supposed to be getting from the
system now of course the system has some
components which we call modules so
these are not components like
transistors and so on these are the kind
of largest components of the system so
for example a computer system will have
a processor and a memory and so on each
of these has components of its own and
so on and for each of these modules we
can specify some behavior that it should
be ideally getting so each model has
some sort of ideal behavior that we will
want to expect from it but of course
real modules will maybe not always
exhibit this ideal behavior so when we
talk about things that make the system
not be dependable we're really talking
about modules deviating from specified
behavior and that causing the system to
deviate so that the delivered service no
longer matches the specified service